<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: pitching | Learning About Making and Selling iOS Apps]]></title>
  <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/categories/pitching/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-07T09:31:35+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://lewisalexander.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lewis Alexander]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to apply for graphic design work]]></title>
    <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/how-to-apply-for-graphic-design-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-07T09:25:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/how-to-apply-for-graphic-design-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re looking for a graphic designer at the moment. We asked around friends and no one had any suitable recommendations and so we turned to the freelance boards. &ldquo;There must be thousands of skilled designers out there&rdquo; we thought.</p>

<p>In fact it turned out that there are plenty of designers out there, and they are happy to take the time to contact us. We expected that we&rsquo;d get a few applications from people who copy and paste responses. <strong>But in fact about 90% of the proposals we received made no effort to address the brief at all.</strong> We didn&rsquo;t receive a single one which addressed every point.</p>

<p>The brief is to redesign our app and make it iOS 7 ready. Here&rsquo;s what we said we wanted:</p>

<ul>
<li>Someone who loves their work and takes great pride in it</li>
<li>A portfolio full of great iOS app designs, iOS icon designs and iOS app marketing material (the initial work is for the UI design, but we&rsquo;ll need the other stuff eventually)</li>
<li>A great communicator who can help us get the most out of the experience</li>
</ul>


<p>As I said we had a lot of people for whom this information didn&rsquo;t seem relevant. Here&rsquo;s what I think they could have done better.</p>

<h2>why do you want this job?</h2>

<p>This is key. As someone building a product I&rsquo;m 100% into it. It&rsquo;s my world. What I want to hear is someone who <em>wants</em> to be part of this.</p>

<p>If you went for a real life job interview the first question you&rsquo;d be asked is: &ldquo;Why do you want to work for this company?&rdquo;. You&rsquo;d expect it and you&rsquo;d have a good answer prepared.</p>

<p>Now applying for freelance work is pretty much like a job interview right? Only without the pressure of a face to face meeting. You have time to sit and answer this question.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you can&rsquo;t think of a reason you want the work then save yourself and the hirer some time and don&rsquo;t apply for the job.</p></blockquote>

<p>Think about it from my perspective: This project is my life, why would I hire someone who doesn&rsquo;t want to work on it?</p>

<p>If you do want the work, put the time into writing something that convinces me of this.</p>

<h2>relevant experience</h2>

<p>The next thing you&rsquo;d get asked in a job interview is &lsquo;why do you think you are suitable for this role?&rsquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>If you don&rsquo;t have the experience asked for then don&rsquo;t waste everybody&rsquo;s time applying for the job</p></blockquote>

<p>If you have similar experience, but not quite what is asked for AND you really want the job then go into detail about why you think it&rsquo;s relevant and put extra emphasis into the &lsquo;why&rsquo; part.</p>

<h2>how to showcase your work</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re at the point where you want the work and can do it you&rsquo;re probably above 50% of the other candidates so far.</p>

<p>But your portfolio has be convincing. There was a few things here that really surprised me that even candidates who came across well didn&rsquo;t do:</p>

<h3>1. don&rsquo;t send a portfolio</h3>

<p>That&rsquo;s right. Think about it from my perspective. I don&rsquo;t want to trawl through your 50Mb PDF file looking for things that are relevant to me.</p>

<blockquote><p>I want to see two or three (or even one) highly relevant piece of work</p></blockquote>

<p>So don&rsquo;t send your whole portfolio, pick out the most relevant things and send those. Include an explanation about why you think those items are relevant. Demonstrating that you understand what the hirer wants will give you a good connection with them which other people won&rsquo;t be getting.</p>

<h3>2. do send graphics that make it clear what the work you&rsquo;ve done is</h3>

<p>This was another surprising one. I&rsquo;m looking for an iPhone app designer right? What do I want to see iPhone screens. I want to see the detail of the UI you&rsquo;ve slaved and crafted. I don&rsquo;t want to see something rendered in 3d or with things obscuring your work.</p>

<p><img src="https://ws.elance.com/file/TrainSmart_MockUp.png?crypted=Y3R4JTNEcG9ydGZvbGlvJTI2ZmlkJTNEODA5NDE2MzclMjZyaWQlM0QtMSUyNnBpZCUzRDQ1MzQ2OTM" title="iPhone Screens" alt="iPhone Screenshots in a 3d fan" /></p>

<p>The screens here look really well designed. At least the first one does. If I tilt my head a bit. The others look like they might be, but it&rsquo;s hard to be sure because they&rsquo;re hidden behind the first one.</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t use nice effects at the expense of making it easy to view your work</p></blockquote>

<h3>3. do send real world examples</h3>

<p>Even better than properly presented graphics is a real live product.</p>

<blockquote><p>Nobody sent us links to apps in the store</p></blockquote>

<p>We had to go and try and find the apps in the store to see if they were real. For an iPhone app in particular, don&rsquo;t even send graphics if you can send a link to the app store.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you can send promo codes too it shows a level of proof and confidence that will be impossible to ignore</p></blockquote>

<p>Don&rsquo;t have promo codes for your previous work? Ask the developer/hirer for a few, even offer to buy them of them. Trust me sending promo codes will make you look great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
