<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: increase profits | Learning About Making and Selling iOS Apps]]></title>
  <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/categories/increase-profits/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-26T20:53:58+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://lewisalexander.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lewis Alexander]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how do we get better?]]></title>
    <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/how-do-we-get-better/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T14:12:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/how-do-we-get-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We sat down in a trendy art cafe in Chiang Mai. We wanted to work out what to do next with the app. We had a few unfinished features and a few unanswered questions. In short we needed some direction.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We started writing on cards all the things we wanted to do in all areas of the app, features, marketing, everything. As we got them down it became clear that there was a kind of hierarchy of goals. And we sorted the cards into the appropriate category.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the hierarchy that we saw:</p>

<p><img src="/user-images/hierachy.png" alt="Make more profit from More Downloads from More Reviews from More Engaged Users
" /></p>

<p>Although they all feed up, it&rsquo;s possible to address things at the higher levels specifically. For example, getting more reviews could come from thinking more carefully about how and when we ask for reviews. And more downloads could come from improved screenshots or app store wording.</p>

<p>This was kind of a revelation for me. As a developer it&rsquo;s so easy to get tied into the ground level view where you want to add features. The reviews thing in particular, we have a bit of code that prompts the user after a number of times of using the app and we thought about the wording and how many uses was ok before asking. But we didn&rsquo;t think much beyond that. Might things like time of day make a difference?  The more we thought about it the more we thought it would.</p>

<p>We also realised there was a lot more analytics we could be collecting to help us understand our customers better and make more informed decisions about which features to include.</p>

<p>So we&rsquo;ve decided to park the new features and focus purely on the science of getting more review and more downloads for a little bit. As well as collecting more data to help us decide how to approach increasing engagement.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the plan:</p>

<ul>
<li>Refine which screens on the app will ask a user for a review. Never ask just when the app opens</li>
<li>Add reporting to know how many times we ask for a review and how many times people say yes, no and later</li>
<li>A/B test the time of day to ask for a review. I have a theory that for our app asking in the afternoon will give better results than in the morning, but I want to test that</li>
<li>Add events for data collection and add goals in analytics</li>
<li>Collect data about which model our users are using. For whatever reason analytics doesn&rsquo;t gather this by default. This is particularly important as iOS 7 approaches as some devices will not be able to upgrade</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
