<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: freelance | Learning About Making and Selling iOS Apps]]></title>
  <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/categories/freelance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-30T12:43:26+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://lewisalexander.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lewis Alexander]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[finding a graphic designer]]></title>
    <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/08/17/finding-a-graphic-designer/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-17T18:12:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/08/17/finding-a-graphic-designer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some reason we thought that finding a graphic designer would be easy…</p>

<p>We&rsquo;d just post on elance, get loads of replies from talented, experienced and readily available people and then pick one and get some great screens designed.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>what we found</h2>

<p>As I mentioned in my <a href="/blog/2013/08/07/how-to-apply-for-graphic-design-work/">last post</a> our experience was a little different and we abandoned elance after a frustrating week.</p>

<p>We then moved onto <a href="www.behance.net">behance</a> and found we had only a slightly better response. We approached one guy whose work we liked, but on speaking with him he didn&rsquo;t feel like a good fit. We had lots of applicants but a lot didn&rsquo;t read the brief or provide what we&rsquo;d asked for.</p>

<p>I then tried looking around on Google. There&rsquo;s obviously plenty of people to sift through &ndash; far too many really -and I went through the first 5 pages of results and contacted a few who I liked. Some weren&rsquo;t available, some said our budget wasn&rsquo;t high enough. The rest just couldn&rsquo;t show us what we wanted to see.</p>

<p>Next I tried <a href="www.linkedin.com">LinkedIn</a>. LinkedIn is  less cut out for this than I would have expected. Surprisingly few people had their actual work shown online. I found a couple of promising people based solely on their CVs (working with Google, Adobe, Apple, etc) and in the end I did find one person who was our runner up choice.</p>

<p>Finally we got an <a href="Greg">applicant</a> we liked on <a href="www.behance.net">behance</a> and after speaking to him on Skype and having a long email conversation with him we&rsquo;ve decided to go ahead with him. We&rsquo;re excited to see how it works out. The phrase <a href="http://paulgraham.com/ds.html">&ldquo;how big could this company get if the founders did the right things?&rdquo;</a> is always in my head when we&rsquo;re making decisions like this. I&rsquo;ll let you know how it goes.</p>

<h2>what we learned</h2>

<p><strong>My biggest take away from this is that we should have allowed a lot more time.</strong> Feeling rushed stressed us out and made making a confident decision a lot harder.</p>

<p>Second, right after we&rsquo;d settled on someone we learned about <a href="www.ooomf.com">ooomf</a>. I&rsquo;d use this next time as it seems to take care of a lot of the hard work for you. I expect the prices would be very high though. (I&rsquo;d love to hear experiences from either hirers or freelancers on this site).</p>

<p>Third, I wouldn&rsquo;t use elance again, not for graphic design anyway. I would spend more time combing through <a href="www.behance.net">behance</a> and <a href="http://dribbble.com">dribble</a> looking for people to approach rather than posting a listing and waiting for reactions.</p>

<p>Finally, although at the time I thought we were clear about our requirements I think with hindsight we could have included more detail up front. More importantly I think we could have been more blunt about ignoring people who didn&rsquo;t send the minimum spec. I&rsquo;d also set a test like &lsquo;include this phrase at the top of your bid&rsquo; to show that candidates have read all the way through the brief.</p>

<p>In short, we&rsquo;ve learned a lot over the past few weeks and we know what we&rsquo;d do differently should we need to hire another designer. But, honestly, I really hope we don&rsquo;t need to go through that process again any time soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to apply for graphic design work]]></title>
    <link href="http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/how-to-apply-for-graphic-design-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-07T09:25:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lewisalexander.github.io/blog/2013/08/07/how-to-apply-for-graphic-design-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re looking for a graphic designer at the moment. When we couldn&rsquo;t get any suitable recommendations from friends we turned to the freelance boards.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>When the job was up and posted we expected to get a few copy and pasted responses. <strong>But in fact about 90% of the proposals we received made no effort to address the brief at all.</strong> Unbelievably, the majority didn&rsquo;t include a message of any kind, they just sent a link to a portfolio.</p>

<p>We haven&rsquo;t received a single one that addressed every point.</p>

<p>The brief was to redesign our app and make it iOS 7 ready. Here&rsquo;s what we said we wanted:</p>

<ul>
<li>Someone who loves their work and takes great pride in it</li>
<li>A portfolio full of great iOS app designs, iOS icon designs and iOS app marketing material (the initial work is for the UI design, but we&rsquo;ll need the other stuff eventually)</li>
<li>Links to live apps in the App Store</li>
<li>A great communicator who can help us get the most out of the experience</li>
</ul>


<p>Straight away, the designers who just fired us a link failed the &lsquo;great communicator&rsquo; test. Here&rsquo;s what I think the rest could have done better.</p>

<h2>why do you want this job?</h2>

<p>This is key. As someone building a product I&rsquo;m 100% into it. I want to hear that the applicant <em>wants</em> to be part of this.</p>

<p>If you went for a real life job interview the first question you&rsquo;d be asked is: &ldquo;Why do you want to work for this company?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Applying for freelance work is pretty much like a job interview, right? Only without the pressure of a face to face meeting.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you can&rsquo;t think of a reason you want the work then save yourself and the hirer some time and don&rsquo;t apply for the job.</p></blockquote>

<p>Think about it from my perspective: This project is my life, why would I hire someone who can&rsquo;t raise enough enthusiasm to tell me why they want to work on it too?</p>

<p>If you do want the work, put the time into writing something that convinces me of this.</p>

<h2>relevant experience</h2>

<p>The next thing you&rsquo;d get asked in a job interview is &ldquo;why do you think you are suitable for this role?&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>If you don&rsquo;t have the experience required, don&rsquo;t apply for the job</p></blockquote>

<p>If you have similar experience, but not quite what is asked for AND you really want the job then go into detail about why you think it&rsquo;s relevant and put extra emphasis into the &lsquo;why&rsquo; part. Sell it to me.</p>

<h2>how to showcase your work</h2>

<p>If you can demonstrate you want to the work and have the required experience, you&rsquo;re probably in the top 50% of candidates so far.</p>

<p>But your portfolio has be convincing. This is your ace in the hole, the one opportunity you have to demonstrate the kind of skills and innovation we&rsquo;re looking for. I was surprised to find that even the few candidates who came across well in other areas didn&rsquo;t take the time to get this right:</p>

<h3>1. don&rsquo;t send a portfolio</h3>

<p>That&rsquo;s right. I&rsquo;m getting more than a hundred responses to my job post, I don&rsquo;t want to have to trawl through your 50Mb PDF file trying to identify the examples that are relevant to me.</p>

<blockquote><p>I want to see two or three (or even one) highly relevant piece of work</p></blockquote>

<p>So don&rsquo;t send your whole portfolio, pick out the most relevant things and send those. Include an explanation about why you think those items are relevant. If you can demonstrate that you understand what the hirer wants, you&rsquo;ll be able to create a much better connection with them.</p>

<h3>2. do send graphics that present your work clearly</h3>

<p>This was another surprising one. I&rsquo;m looking for an iPhone app designer, right? So I want to  see iPhone screens. I want to see the detail of the UI you&rsquo;ve slaved over and crafted. I don&rsquo;t want to see something rendered in 3D or something so over-designed that it obscures your work.</p>

<p><img src="https://ws.elance.com/file/TrainSmart_MockUp.png?crypted=Y3R4JTNEcG9ydGZvbGlvJTI2ZmlkJTNEODA5NDE2MzclMjZyaWQlM0QtMSUyNnBpZCUzRDQ1MzQ2OTM" title="iPhone Screens" alt="iPhone Screenshots in a 3d fan" /></p>

<p>The screens here look really well designed. At least the first one does… if I tilt my head a bit. The others look like they might be well designed, but it&rsquo;s hard to be sure because they&rsquo;re hidden.</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t use nice effects at the expense of making it easy to view your work</p></blockquote>

<h3>3. do send real world examples</h3>

<p>Even better than properly presented graphics is a  live product. In fact, if you have links to a product in the App Store, you don&rsquo;t even need to send graphics.</p>

<blockquote><p>Only 2% of applications sent us links to apps in the store</p></blockquote>

<p>That&rsquo;s even though we specified that we wanted to see links in the brief. For the rest, we had to dig around ourselves to check if their designs had indeed made it into the store. It&rsquo;s a lame excuse to say you can&rsquo;t provide a link because you were &lsquo;just&rsquo; the designer &ndash; if we could find them (eventually), then so could you.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you can send promo codes too it shows a level of proof and confidence that will be impossible to ignore</p></blockquote>

<p>Don&rsquo;t have promo codes for your previous work? Ask the developer/hirer for a few, even offer to buy them of them. Trust me, sending promo codes will make you look great.</p>

<p><a href="http://under30ceo.com/">Under 30 SEO</a> wrote a <a href="http://under30ceo.com/hacking-elance-the-step-by-step-guide-to-how-i-made-23700-in-4-weeks/">great piece</a>. There&rsquo;s no excuse people!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
