<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ios | Learning About Making and Selling iOS Apps]]></title>
  <link href="http://lewis-smith.github.io/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lewis-smith.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-24T15:58:11+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://lewis-smith.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lewis Smith]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ios 7.1 will allow developers to release updates more often and reduce nagware]]></title>
    <link href="http://lewis-smith.github.io/blog/2013/12/24/ios-7-dot-1-will-allow-developers-to-release-updates-more-often-and-reduce-nagware/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-24T15:31:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://lewis-smith.github.io/blog/2013/12/24/ios-7-dot-1-will-allow-developers-to-release-updates-more-often-and-reduce-nagware</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With iOS 7.1 Apple has changed the App Store to show the overall star rating for apps. Currently ratings are only for the latest update. This is great for developers and users alike.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The current system punishes devs for releasing an update by reseting their star rating to 0. This means they hold off on updates until they have enough features and fixes to make it worth the &lsquo;hit&rsquo; of resetting their stars.</p>

<p><img src="/user-images/app-store.png" alt="App store change" /></p>

<p>With auto update introduced in iOS 7 developers can now push out updates almost transparently to users. With the ratings change we can do that without affecting our status in the App Store, so there&rsquo;s nothing to lose by having all the latest bug fixes released to customers.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s been a lot of talk lately about apps nagging or pestering users to leave reviews, with this change the need to update reviews will be taken away which hopefully will reduce nagware.</p>

<p>All in all this is a small but highly significant change for iOS 7.1.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
